Guide to the Eric Lindbloom Hudson Valley Panoramics Collection, 1969-2021 (bulk 1969-2001)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Eric Lindbloom Hudson Valley Panoramics Collection
1969-2021
1969-2001
Lindbloom, Eric, 1934-
36 boxes (20 cubic feet)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Photographic prints, negatives, contact sheets, and ephemera relating to Eric Lindbloom's photography of the Hudson River Valley of New York State.
Biographical Note
Eric Lindbloom (1934-2020) was born in Detroit, Michigan. He graduated from the University of Michigan and studied photography with Paul Caponigro, 1969-1971. Lindbloom's photograph collections include Angels at the Arno (1994), Pacem in Terris (1999), and Salt Grass (2008). He also collaborated on several books with his wife, writer Nancy Willard, including The River That Runs Two Ways (2000) and Waves (2014).
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of photographic prints, negatives, contact sheets, and ephemera relating to Eric Lindbloom's photography of New York State's Hudson River Valley.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Subjects:
Landscape photography--New York (State)--Hudson River Valley
Document types:
Contact sheets; Negatives (photographs]; Panoramic photographs; Photographic prints
Places:
Hudson River Valley (N.Y. and N.J.)--Pictorial works
VCL Categories:
Art and Artists; Local History; Nature and Natural History
Encoding Information
Encoded by Mark Seidl, April 2020. Updated by Mark Seidl, June 2021. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, February 2024.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Eric Lindbloom (M2019-004) and James Lindbloom (M2021-002).
Series List
- Series I. Limited Edition/Matted Prints, 1971-1999; (Boxes 1-10)
- Series II. Work Prints, 1969-2012, undated; (Boxes 10-19]
- Series III. Contact Sheets, 2004, undated; (Boxes 13, 19-22]
- Series IV. Negatives, 1969-2006; (Boxes 20-33]
- Series V. Ephemera, 1984-2021; (Boxes 8, 19]
Container List
- SERIES I. LIMITED EDITION/MATTED PRINTS
  - Apple Bin Orchard, undated; [(2) prints; 11 x 20 inches] (Box 1 (Oversize))
  - Backstop, Hasbrouck Park, 1990; [(2) signed prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 1 (Oversize))
  - Henry Hudson Considers Moving to the Mall, Kingston, NY, 1990; [signed; 8 x 19 inches] (Box 1 (Oversize))
  - Hutton Brickyard, Kingston, NY, 2/15, 1991; [signed (2) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 1 (Oversize))
  - Light Woods, Saratoga Battlefield, 1996; [11 x 19 inches] (Box 1 (Oversize))
  - Opus 40, undated; [(2) prints; 19 x 8 inches] (Box 1 (Oversize))
  - Tivoli Bays, Annandale-on-Hudson, NY, undated; [(3) prints; 11 x 20 inches] (Box 1 (Oversize))
  - Hutton Park, Kingston, NY, 1990; [(2) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 2 (Oversize))
  - Kingston, NY, swimming beach, undated; [8 x 14 inches] (Box 2 (Oversize))
  - Paper Mill, Glens Falls, NY, 1992; [8 x 20 inches] (Box 2 (Oversize))
  - Rodman Road, Craryville, NY, 2/15, 1996; [11 x 20 inches] (Box 2 (Oversize))
  - Winston Farm, Saugerties, NY, 11/15, 4/15, 1989; [(3) prints; 11 x 20 inches] (Box 2 (Oversize))
  - Burnt Field, Bemis Heights, Saratoga, NY, 3/15, 4/15, 5/15, 1992; [(4) prints; 11 x 20 inches] (Box 3 (Oversize))
  - Frozen Inlet, Kingston, NY, 3/15, 1991; [11 x 20 inches] (Box 3 (Oversize))
  - John Neilson's Farm, Saratoga Battlefield, NY, 5/15, 1992; [8 x 20 inches] (Box 3 (Oversize))
  - Lueken Jenkins Orchard, New Paltz, 3/15, 1991; [8 x 20 inches] (Box 3 (Oversize))
  - Undercliff, Mohonk, NY, 3/15, 1991; [(2) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 3 (Oversize))
  - Alf Ever's Yard, Woodstock, NY, 4/15, 1995; [11 x 20 inches] (Box 4 (Oversize))
  - Burger Hill, Rhinebeck, NY, 1997; [11 x 20 inches] (Box 4 (Oversize))
  - Mead Orchard, Red Hook, NY, 2/15, 1997; [11 x 20 inches] (Box 4 (Oversize))
  - Passageway, Opus 40, 3/15, 1993; [(2) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 4 (Oversize))
  - Peach Hill, Poughkeepsie, NY, 2/15, 1995; [8 x 20 inches] (Box 4 (Oversize))
  - Back of the Orchard, Ulster Park, NY, 1988; [(2) prints; 11 x 20 inches] (Box 5 (Oversize))
  - Benmarl Vineyard, Marlboro, NY, 5/15, 1991; [(5) prints, one unmatted, one signed; 11 x 20 inches] (Box 5 (Oversize))
  - Black Willow, Wethersfield, Amenia, 4/15, 1997; [(2) prints, one unmatted, one signed; 20 x 11 inches] (Box 5 (Oversize))
  - Constitution Marsh, Cold Spring, NY, 12/15, 1995; [(2) prints, one unmatted, one signed; 11 x 20 inches] (Box 5 (Oversize))
  - Copse, Saratoga Battlefield, undated; [11 x 20 inches] (Box 5 (Oversize))
  - Winston Farm, Saugerties, NY, 1989; [11 x 20 inches] (Box 5 (Oversize))
  - Apple Trees, Marlboro, NY or Milton Turnpike Orchard, 3/15, 1998; [11 x 20 inches] (Box 6 (Oversize))
  - Birch Trees, Athens, NY, A/P, 1999; [11 x 20 inches] (Box 6 (Oversize))
  - Cohotate Preserve, Athens, NY, A/P, 1999; [11 x 20 inches] (Box 6 (Oversize))
  - Giant Sculpture by Roy Kanwit, Spencertown, NY, 1/15, 1998; [11 x 20 inches] (Box 6 (Oversize))
  - Stone Circle, Wing's Castle, Millbrook, NY, 1997; [11 x 20 inches] (Box 6 (Oversize))
  - Wawayanda River, Warwick, NY, 2/15, 1998; [(2) prints; 11 x 20 inches] (Box 6 (Oversize))
  - Apple Tree, Poughkeepsie, NY or DeWitt's Yard,1/15, 1995; [signed; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 7 (Oversize))
  - Iona Island, undated; [8 x 20 inches] (Box 7 (Oversize))
  - Paper Mill, Glens Falls, NY, 4/15, 1994; [8 x 20 inches] (Box 7 (Oversize))
  - Vineyard Under Snow, Germantown, NY, 1993; [8 x 20 inches] (Box 7 (Oversize))
  - False Hellebore, Keene, NY, unidentified orchard, 1971; [11 x 14 inches] (Folder 10.2)
  - Fifth Ward Memorial, 1990; [signed; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 8 (Oversize))
  - Forsyth Park, Kingston, NY, 2/15, 1990; [11 x 20 inches] (Box 8 (Oversize))
  - Ice Floes and Hudson, Kingston, NY, A/P, 1991; [(2) prints,one signed; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 7 (Oversize))
  - Lean-to, Bowdoin Park, Wappingers Falls, NY, 1993; [signed; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 8 (Oversize))
  - Rockeby, Barrytown, NY 2/15, 1921; [(2) prints, one signed; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 8 (Oversize))
  - Sycamore, Bowdoin Park, 3/15, 1992; [signed; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 8 (Oversize))
  - Sledding, Hasbrouck Park, 1991; [signed; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 8 (Oversize))
  - Frank Sass Memorial Field, Left Field Foul Pole, Block Park, Kingston, NY, 1990; [signed; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 9 (Oversize))
  - Lueken Jenkins Orchard II, New Paltz, 1991; [(2) prints, signed; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 9 (Oversize))
  - Lueken Jenkins Orchard, New Paltz, 1991; [signed; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 9 (Oversize))
  - Visitation, Kingston Point Beach, 1990; [signed; 8 x 20 inches] (Box 9 (Oversize))
- SERIES II. WORK PRINTS
  - A Day in the Life of Ulster County Project, Lake Hill, Ulster Park, Esopus, Milton, Kingston, Saugerties, New Paltz, undated (Folder 19.19)
  - Almost Falls, April-May 1969 (Folders 19.16-19.18)
  - Wilderstein, Fir Trees, Cohotate Preserve, Burger Hill, John Neilson's Farm, undated; [8 x 10 inches and smaller] (Folder 10.1)
  - Kingston Nancy Willard and Eric Lindbloom portraiture, Jenkins Orchard, Alf Evers, Cohotate, Vassar, Opus 40, includes handwritten notations on Kingston beach print, undated; [8 x 10 inches] (Folder 10.3)
  - Benmarl, Kingston, NY, Germantown, NY, Pacem in Terris, undated; [8 x 20 inches] (Folders 10.4-10.6)
  - Kingston Point Beach, undated; [(5) prints; 11 x 20 inches] (Folder 11.1 (Oversize))
  - Kingston, NY (sledding), Fifth Ward Memorial, undated; [(10) prints; 11 x 20 inches] (Folder 11.2 (Oversize))
  - Kingston Ice Floes, Peach Hill, undated; [(8) prints; 11 x 20 inches] (Folder 11.3 (Oversize))
  - Kingston, NY streetscapes, undated; [(8) prints; 11 x 20 inches] (Folder 11.4 (Oversize))
  - Winston Farm, Undercliff, Mohonk, Benmarl, undated; [(19) prints; 11 x 20 inches and smaller] (Folder 11.5 (Oversize))
  - Germantown, Vineyard Under Snow, [untitled woodland landscape], undated; [(8) prints; 11 x 20 inches] (Folder 11.6 (Oversize))
  - Kanit sculpture, Spencertown, NY, undated; [(3) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 12.1)
  - Kingston streetscapes, Congress Park, Saratoga, undated; [(9) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 12.2)
  - Kingston, NY, Wethersfield Estate, undated; [(9) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 12.3)
  - Lueken Jenkins Farm, Harry Cornish Garden, undated; [(12) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 12.4)
  - Mary Frank property, undated; [(18) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 12.5)
  - Mohonk, Storm King, undated; [(12) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 12.6)
  - Mohonk, undated; [(8) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 12.7)
  - Opus 40, unidentified orchard, undated; [(10) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 12.8)
  - Opus 40, Saratoga streetscape, Innisfree Garden, undated; [(17) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 12.9)
  - Pacem in Terris, Murphy Roseman Garden, undated; [(19) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 12.10)
  - Saratoga Battlefield, Burnt Field, Swing, undated; [(9) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 12.11)
  - Vassar College Alumni House, Olana, Fir tree forest, undated; [(13) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 12.12)
  - Half Your Age Series, Poughkeepsie, NY, Vassar College, Eric Lindbloom portrait, 2012; [(37) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folders 13.2-13.3)
  - Jenkins Orchard, Apple Trees, Marlboro, NY, undated; [(18) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 13.4)
  - Kingston, NY, Forsyth Park, architecture, water front, undated; [(24) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 13.5)
  - Putnam Land Conservancy, 2004; [(20) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 13.6)
  - Taconic Sculpture Park, Kingston, NY, streetscapes, orchards, undated; [(14) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 13.7)
  - Winston Farm, Saugerties, Burger Hill, Iona Island, Kingston Bridge, Rodman Road, Market Street Industrial Park, Vassar Observatory, Neilson's Farm, undated; [(35) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 13.8)
  - Alf Ever's Yard, Woodstock, Wawayanda Creek, undated; [(27) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 14.1)
  - Benmarl Winery, undated; [(24) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folders 14.2-14.3)
  - Kingston Bridge, Saugerties, Winston Farm, unidentified figures, group portraiture, undated; [(36) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 14.4)
  - Pacem in Terris, Warwick, NY, Esopus, NY, Kingston, NY, undated; [(16) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 14.5)
  - Wave Hill, Columbia County Book Barn, Hurley Corn Maze, undated; [(21) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 14.6)
  - Apple tree, Dewitt's Yard, Soldier's Memorial Fountain, Poughkeepsie, NY, undated; [(5) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 15.1 (Oversize))
  - Block Park, Kingston, NY, 1990; [(15) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 15.2 (Oversize))
  - Burnt Hill, Bemis Heights, Roosevelt Historic Site, Hyde Park, Bowdoin Park, Wappingers Falls, undated; [(8) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 15.3 (Oversize))
  - Constitution Marsh, Kingston Point, Benmarl Winery, undated; [(8) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 15.4 (Oversize))
  - Kingston, NY, Academy Green, undated; [(6) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 15.5 (Oversize))
  - Kingston, NY, playground, Kingston Point Park, undated; [(10) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 15.6 (Oversize))
  - Kingston, NY, Hasbrouck Park, undated; [(4) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 15.7 (Oversize))
  - Winston Farm, Saugerties, NY, Kingston Point, undated; [(8) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 15.8 (Oversize))
  - Black Willow, Wethersfield, undated; [(4) prints; 20 x 11 inches] (Folder 16.1 (Oversize))
  - Burger Hill, Rhinebeck, Lueken Jenkins Farm, undated; [(9) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 16.2 (Oversize))
  - Hudson Valley Postcards, undated (Folders 19.10-19.15)
  - Hutton Brickyard, Kingston, NY, Rokeby, Barrytown, NY, undated; [(6) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 16.3 (Oversize))
  - Iona Island, undated; [(5) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 16.4 (Oversize))
  - Kingston, NY, waterfront, Ice Floes, undated; [(13) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 16.5 (Oversize))
  - Kingston, NY, waterfront, Forsyth Park, undated; [(6) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 16.6 (Oversize))
  - Olana (?), undated; [(1) print; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 16.7 (Oversize))
  - Opus 40, Saugerties, NY, undated; [(6) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 16.8 (Oversize))
  - Papermill, Glen Falls, NY, undated; [(3) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 16.9 (Oversize))
  - Saugerties, undated; [(6) prints; 8 x 20 inches] (Folder 16.10 (Oversize))
  - Hudson, NY, Hudson alleys, 2007; [(11) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 17.1)
  - Kingston, NY, beaches, undated; [(18) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 17.2)
  - Kingston, NY, playgrounds, storage tanks, undated; [(29) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 17.3)
  - Kingston, NY, Kingston Point, Stone Circle, Wings Castle, undated; [(13) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 17.4)
  - Kingston, NY, waterfront, Rondout, Ice Floes, undated; [(26) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 17.5)
  - Kingston City Hall, undated; [(59) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folders 17.6-17.8)
  - Kingston, NY, baseball fields, Block Park, undated; [(20) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 18.1)
  - Kingston, NY, beaches, swimming, undated; [(24) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folders 18.2-18.3)
  - Kingston, NY, parks, monuments, statuary, undated; [(22) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 18.4)
  - Kingston, NY, streetscapes, snow sledding, undated; [(21) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 18.5)
  - Snapshots, Nancy Willard, Eric Lindbloom, Sasha Bush, undated (Folder 19.9)
  - Wilderstein, Rhinebeck, NY, undated; [(56) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folders 18.6-18.9)
- SERIES III. CONTACT SHEETS
  - Dutchess Land Conservancy, 2004 (Folder 19.1)
  - Hudson Valley Panoramics, undated (Folders 20.1-22.11)
  - Half Your Age, Peach Hill, Vassar, undated (Folder 19.2)
  - Mohonk, Minnewaska, undated (Folder 19.3)
  - Murphy Roseman Garden, Jenkins Orchard, Benmarl, Shady, NY, undated; [(9) prints; 11 x 14 inches] (Folder 13.1)
- SERIES IV. NEGATIVES
  - Graveyard, Frank's Pear Trees, Wethersfield, Marlboro, Stone Slab Houses, Minnewaska, Saratoga, Vassar, Millbrook, Roosevelt, Bowdoin, Columbia County, Benmarl, Innisfree, Opus 40, Bear Mountain, Amberdale Vineyard, Clinton Vineyard, 1992-1993 (Box 23)
  - Kingston Parks, Block Park, Forsyth, Hutton, Fifth Ward, Rondout, Hasbrook, Fireman's Park, Academy Green, Cornell, West Strand, 1990-1991 (Box 24)
  - Minnewaska, Mohonk, Winston Farm, Esopus, Kingston, Benmarl, Almost Falls, Shawangunks, Dutchess Land Conservancy, Brick House Farm, Buttercup Sanctuary, Lake Hill, New Paltz, 1969-2001 (Box 25)
  - Clermont, Olana, Vassar, Mohonk, Marlboro, Bear Mountain, Sawkill Creek, Ashokan, Kingston Point, Pacem in Terris, Cold Spring, Mid Hudson Bridge, Tivoli, Rhinecliff, Iona Island, Ferncliff, Kinderhook, Athens, 1993-1994 (Box 26)
  - Schodack Landing, Taconic Sculpture, Harry and Cathy's, Stonehenge, Minnewaska, Pacem in Terris, Storm King, Birch, Athens, Battlefield, Schaghticoke, Vassar, Iona Island, Poet's Walk, Woodstock, Kingston, Burger Hill, Wallkill, Saugerties, Mohonk, Schuylerville, Mill Creek, Ann Morse's Yard, Lueken Jenkins, Peach Hill, Hudson, 1998-2001 (Box 27)
  - Kingston Parks, Block Park, Forsyth, Hutton, Fifth Ward, Rondout, Hasbrouck, Fireman's Park, Academy Green, Cornell, West Strand, 1990-1991 (Box 28)
  - Vassar Farm, Wappingers Creek, Hudson, NY, Mary Frank's Yard, Minnewaska, Sam's Point, Berger Hill, Schoharie Creek, Lexington, Phoenicia, New Paltz, Shenandoah Farm, Dutchess Quarry, Kingston Point, Millbrook Vineyard, Hyde Park, Wethersfield, Amenia, Corn Maze, Hurley, Kinderhook, Milton, Orchard Corral, Wilderstein, 2002-2006 (Box 29)
  - Star Island, Nancy at Mohonk, Schodic, ME, Little Moose Island, Vassar, Mohonk, Alaska, Cape Cod, Denali, Garrison, Jerome's House, Benmarl, Isle Vogels, Cape Cod, 1989-1995 (Box 30)
  - Winston Farm, Kingston, Leuken Jenkins, Mohonk, Benmarl, Vassar Farm, Undercliff, Hasbrouck Park, Soldiers Park, Wave Hill, Cape Cod, Storm King, West Point, Millbrook, Hutton Brickyard, High Falls, Undercliff, 1991 (Box 31)
  - Half Your Age, Vassar, Peach Hill, Millbrook, Olana, Coopers Lake, Rondout, Sawkill Creek, Saugerties, Untermyer, Apple Bin, Berger Hill, Wappingers Falls, Minnewaska, Burnt Field Saratoga, Ulster Park, Warwick Orchard, Milton Turnpike, Hudson, Rhinebeck, Schoharie, Saratoga Battlefield, Storm King, Mandara Orchard, Stuyvesant Landing, 1997-1998 (Box 32)
  - Alf Evers, Leuken Jenkins, Peach Hill, Flat Iron, Peach Hill, Constitution Marsh, Germantown, Saugerties, Oil Tanks, Kingston Point, Van De Bovenkamp, Millbrook, Cementon, Kingston, Olana, Saratoga, Hudson, Book Barn, Mill Creek, Chuck Huffman's, Kingston, Pacem in Terris, Wilderstein, Manitoga, Rhinebeck, Innisfree, Poet's Walk, Benmarl, Ogden Mills, 1995-1996 (Box 33)
  - Athens, Apple Bin, Kingston, Rondout, Van Winkle, Peach Hill, Milton, Benmarl, Minnewaska, Saugerties, Wappingers Falls, Olana, Hudson, Bonticou Crag, Kanwit, Manitoga, Wallkill, 1994-1995 (Box 34)
  - Wilderstein, Saugerties, Kingston Point, Bear Mountain, Balmville, Lunt's Oak, Peterskill, Pacem in Terris, Wethersfield, Danskammer, Jenkins Orchard, Alf Evers, Wappingers, Wings Castle, Rhinebeck, Kinderhook, Saratoga Battlefield, Hudson, Amenia, Elena Zang's, Benmarl, Hudson, Magic Meadow, Breakneck, Danskammer, Mandara, Rondout, Innisfree, Marlboro, Alf's, 1995-1997 (Box 35)
  - Regency, Benmarl, Vassar, Vanderbilt, Bowdoin, Mohonk, Mary Frank's Yard, Saratoga, Glen Falls, Alumni House, Pacem in Terris, Columbia Apple Orchard, 1989-1992 (Box 36)
- SERIES V. EPHEMERA
  - Exhibition posters, 1984-2010; [(4) posters, signed] (Box 8 (Oversize))
  - Avis map of NYC area, undated (Folder 19.4)
  - Lindbloom exhibition flyer, Woodstock, NY, 1984 (Folder 19.5)
  - Lindbloom exhibition postcards, 1990-2021 (Folders 19.6-19.7)
  - Wilderstein, maps, flyers, correspondence, 1988-1989 (Folder 19.8)